

# **Adam Drescher Nuclear Engineer**



30 January 1994



awdrescher@gmail.com



+1 (603) 769-9079



https://awdrescher.github.io

### About Me ——

I have research experience with radiation transport modeling, computational data analytics applied to nuclear forensics, and lab experience developing novel radiation detection systems. Currently I apply data analytic techniques to improve analysis of nuclear safeguards data. I have experience collaborating with teams in research and development as well as application-based environments.

## Education —

PhD, Engineering University of Texas at Austin Dec 2019 | GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

MS, Engineering University of Texas at Austin May 2017 | GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

BS, Physics University of Texas at Austin Dec 2015 | GPA: 3.7 / 4.0

### Skills –

Laboratory: Gamma-ray spectrometry, Neutron activation analysis

Data Analytics: Machine learning, data science, predictive analytics,

data wrangling

Simulations: Neutron transport, nuclear fuel cycle, gamma-ray

emissions

#### Work Experience and Internships

2020 Postdoc in Nuclear Forensics Modeling Oak Ridge National Laboratory Leveraged advanced data science and machine learning techniques to develop new capabilities for nuclear safeguards.

2017-2019 PhD Graduate Student University of Texas at Austin Developed autonomous, novel, ensemble-based machine learning monitoring systems for uranium assay of spent nuclear fuel with errors as low as 0.05%.

2016-2017 Master's Graduate Student University of Texas at Austin Built and characterized the performance of a gamma radiation detection system for fission product measurements with 10 times improvement on count-rate compared to state-of-the-art.

2016-2019 Teaching Assistant University of Texas at Austin Served as TA for five undergraduate and graduate courses. Presented up to 50% of all lectures, guided students through laboratory experiments, graded assignments and exams.

2016, 2017 Summer Research Intern Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education, TN 2017: Performed statistical analysis on Relevance Vector Machine models for inferring nuclear reactor core burnup based on isotopic measurements and with unknown sampling position. 2016: Performed Least Squares Regression on gamma-ray measure-

ments to quantify uranium and plutonium contents of irradiated materials.

#### Publications and Presentations

2020 Institute for Nuclear Materials Management

> Leveraging Machine Learning Techniques for the Characterization of Irradiated Uranium: A Case Study of Analysis Methods for Nuclear Safeguards and Nuclear Forensics

Institute for Nuclear Materials Management

Machine Learning Approaches on Nuclear Material Accounting Data from Irradiation and Reprocessing

European Research Reactor Conference

The Complete Neutron Activation Analysis Laboratory: Thermal, Epithermal, Cyclic, Compton Suppression, Gamma-Gamma Coincidence and Prompt Gamma Facilities and Specific Radioprotection Guidelines

2019 **Doctoral Dissertation** 

> Leveraging Machine Learning Techniques for the Characterization of Irradiated Uranium: A Case Study of Prediction Methods for Nuclear Safeguards and Nuclear Forensics

2018 Journal of Radioanalytical and Nuclear Chemistry Gamma-gamma coincidence in neutron activation analysis

26th International Conference on Nuclear Engineering

Revamping of a Graduate Radiochemistry Course for Nuclear Forensics Applications

2017 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium and Medical Imaging Conference Developing Support Vector Machine Prediction Capabilities of Uranium Enrichment Based on Gamma-Gamma Coincidence Signatures

Master's Thesis

Characterization of LaBr<sub>3</sub>:Ce Detectors in a Gamma-Gamma Coincidence Configuration

**Applied Radiation and Isotopes** 

Gamma-gamma coincidence performance of LaBr3:Ce scintillation detectors vs HPGe detectors in high count-rate scenarios

Global International Nuclear Fuel Cycle Conference

Modeling a U.S. Equilibrium Closed Fuel Cycle with Waste Product

Comparisons